## SHAHID HUSSAIN SHAH

<u>Srinagar J&K | +91-9906759062| shahidhussain\_shah@yahoo.in</u> 01-02-1989

Sales & Distribution, Training, Retail, Team management

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Talented and skilled professional with in depth experience of over 10 years in the Retail, Sales and business development and training assignments. Evolving new methodology and goal oriented initiatives to produce the results for the organization.

Possess deep knowledge and experience in market expertise, Managing and implementing the market behavior and ongoing business trends in the work process, Project managing, Data handling.

#### **CORE SKILLS**

Positive attitude, Problem Solving, Decision making, Communication skills, Team work, Self-management, Willingness to Learn, Critical Thinking, Flexibility, Responsibility.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# Sr. SALES MANAGER MARCH 2023

- > Setting and monitoring sales objectives
- Providing sales strategies, feedback, and marketing plans.
- ➤ Contributing to meeting sales target, keeping up-to-date with industry developments.
- Answering customer queries, mediating disputes with customers.

## HOTEL WATERVIBE PAHALGAM Manager /CO-Lease Owner May 2022

- > Overseeing personnel, including receptionists, kitchen staff, and office employees.
- Monitoring employee performance and conducting regular evaluations to help improve customer service.
- ➤ Collecting payments and maintaining records of budgets, funds, and expenses.
- Welcoming and registering guests once they arrive.
- Resolving issues regarding hotel services, amenities, and policies.
- Organizing activities and assigning responsibilities to employees to ensure productivity.
- Creating and applying a marketing strategy to promote the hotel's services and amenities.
- > Evaluating hotel performance and ensuring compliance with health and safety rules.
- Partaking in financial activities, including establishing room rates, setting budgets

## **RELIANCE (JIO MART DIGITAL)**

## **Assistant Manager/Team Lead**

#### **NOV 2021**

- Spearheading the Reliance jio mart digital project for South Kashmir as Assistant Manager/Team Lead .
- Generating leads and orders for Jio phone next and testing Jio mart beta version for launch
- Managing a team of 16 sales executives/ Jio mart officers, Generating sales revenue from them
- > Engaging the retailers for participation/on boarding in reliance jio mart business.
- Ensuring timely deliveries and services for the leads and orders received through JMD.

#### **OPPO**

#### **SEP 2018-OCT 2021**

## **Assistant Manager/Team lead**

- > Looking after the Assignments for the Trainers of Jammu and Kashmir Region.
- > Taking care of Territory sales of the market and monitoring the Growth.
- > Brand promotion through the team in form of different activities and generating

- business out of these activities.
- To maintain the overall quality of team, To do TNA and TNI and work and accordingly planning the work.

#### OPPO

#### **APR 2016-SEP2018**

#### **Senior Trainer**

- Looking out for the training assignment for the Kashmir and Ladakh valley
- > Taking care of the whole sales team and dealers
- Motivating the team to generate revenue by innovative marketing strategies.
- ➤ Handling a team 03 Route trainers and 220 sales team members and achieving an overall 95% result in every session.
- Assisting the team in every day corporate activities.
- Organizing different events and contests on behalf of the company.
- ➤ Handling the launching events of the company in my operating area.
- Taking feedback from dealers and distributors and giving constructive inputs to the company.

#### **SAMSUNG**

### **AUG 2011-MAR 2016**

#### SAMSUNG CONSULTANT

- Overseeing company-owned showroom.
- Handling of customer queries.
- Sales monitoring as per the targets assigned by the Retail Head.
- Overall responsibility for smooth running of the customer care operation.
- Handling a team of executives
- New promotional activities to enhance walk-ins to generate sales.
- Awarded as "Best Samsung Experience Consultant" in certification by Samsung Electronics India Ltd with above 90% grades.

## NOKIA JAN 2011-AUG 2011

#### **SALES PROMOTER**

- > Above par target achievements every month
- > Earned a reputation by providing better customer service in my area of operations

## **EDUCATION**

- Post-graduation in commerce.
- Bachelors in commerce.
- One year diploma in international business organization.
- One year diploma in computer application and maintenance.

## **INTERESTS**

- Mountain hiking
- Bike riding
- Exploring things/places (travelling)
- Adventure sports
- Reading and learning
- Group discussions
- Music

## **REFRENCES**

> References and supported documents available on inquest